you successfully disable the valve volume set of copy in the machine, so the organization
can't able to reboot, sorry, recover any data from the cloud services or the backup data.
But the organization can do one thing, they can enable the safeboard mode. Many of them
are here about this safeboard mode. So if our primary machine has any issue, if it's
corrupted, we have an option to get into the safeboard mode, right? What will do? If the
primary operating system was corrupted, we will use some kind of options in the boot options
like this and we can enter through the safeboard mode, safe mode with networking, safe mode
with command problem. So most of the organization machines, it was enabled, the safeboard mode
was enabled, but in our home machines, this was disabled, okay, defaultly. So here
you can see an option, yeah, let me, I will show you how to, how to enter this, enter
under the safeboard. So this is one of the, the victim of ransomware threat actors, the ransomware
threat actors will only primarily targeting this safeboard mode, because they are going
to encrypt the machine, right? They are going to, they are going to delete the shadow
copies, delete the distracting the data and they are also, they are deleting the safeboard
mode, right? So if they can able to delete, disable the safeboard mode, the organization
machine, what they have encrypted, what they have compromised and installed the ransomware,
the organization can't able to recover that machine. That's the scenario, right? Because
if the safe, if there is no safeboard mode, the primary operating system get encrypted with
and encrypted by Akira or some kind of ransomware. So the organization, well, organization
have few possibilities to do. One is, they need to rebuild the machine and they need
to recover the data. The other is, they need to enter into the safeboard mode to login
into the machine. So if they do not have both the options, they are previously disabled
the valing shadow copies, you have deleted the valing shadow copies. So in this video,
they are disabling the safe mode, okay? So in your primary machine, you can find the
safe mode in, by giving Windows plus R, you must come to here and once they must come to
get loaded, just go to the boot. So here you can see that in primary machines, like
home machines, differently, the safeboard mode has been disabled, we didn't check any safe
board mode, right? We didn't change anything. The similar thing will be there in my primary
machine because, right? So it also has the same, it also has the same thing, right?
So the thing is, they can delete the safeboard mode using the BCD edit, one of an utility
in Windows slash ENUM. So if I do this one, so here you can find the Windows boot manager,
it's showing some kind of information. So recovery enabled is no and isolated context
is no and, and fibroes are auto, so it was giving some kind of information about the Windows
bootloader, but we know that, let's check the MSConf, we know that the safeboard mode
was already disabled in this machine, right? So if the threat actors need to disable
the safeboard mode, they will choose one command, this is the single command, okay, this
is the single command, they will choose a safeboard mode to disable.
Let me execute this command and see what I was getting. So it will show, it will show
a failure lock and error occur attempting to delete the specific data element, element
not found, because we do not have the safeboard mode enabled, right? So we do not have
safeboard mode, that was enabled, so it was already disabled, okay, so we don't need to
delete any values, we are already disabled. So the reason I showed this video, because you
need to understand, if you see this command in any kind of invovolutions or a parent, you
need to know there is some kind of activity has been happened, okay. So this is how the
threat actors will be removing and modifying your machine before delivering their answer,
because they need to prepare the machine for everything. They will not use any possibilities
for an organization to recover or rebuild, rebuild the machine. So once the ransomware has
been properly executed. So that's all about this one, let's hop off from here and we'll
We continue our discussion in the next video.
See you guys, bye-bye.